# **Parth Bhodia**

<u>parthbhodia.com</u> | <u>LinkedIn/in/parthbhodia</u> <u>GitHub</u>

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I am a Software Developer with over 5 years of experience in HTML, CSS, SASS, SCSS, Typescript, Javascript, Node Js, Python, AWS, Java (Springboot). I am proficient with modern frameworks such as Vue Js, Nuxt and React Js and experience with REST APIs and GraphQL.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Fullstack Developer**

Eccalon LLC - Service based company

May 2022 - Present Remote

Location: Jersey City, NJ United States

Email: parthbhodia08@gmail.com | Mobile: +1 4439294371

- Developed a personalized knowledge assistant ChatBOT that uses large language models (GPT) and vector databases (Pinecone) to predict the success rate of a vendor based on historical data, helping vendors prioritize high-probability contracts. Reduced time-to-information retrieval by 50%, improving decision-making speed and accuracy for clients.
- Designed and implemented a Postgres schema for a CMS management system to efficiently manage and display data from database with 1 lakh+ users.
- Engineered a secure Login and Registration system with JWT authentication using AWS Amplify, Cognito, API Gateway, and Lambda Services.
- Developed and deployed dynamic AWS Lambda functions to generate HTML content with Open Graph metadata, enhancing social media sharing and SEO for a sports news platform.
- Integrated Stripe payment processing into our NLSE (Sports Entertainment) website to accept tickets for matches and events.
- Implemented frontend solutions using HTMX and Vue.js, ensuring seamless dynamic interactions without requiring full page reloads for Project Spectrum (Govt. Website).

## **Research Assistant - Software Developer**

University of Maryland, Baltimore County

Jan 2022 - Dec 2022 Halethorpe, MD, US

- Developed a framework for GIS-based visualization of detecting enemy objects using Elastic Search and Kibana. During this project, I gained a deep understanding of Elastic Search's powerful search capabilities, its scalability, and how it can be used to store and visualize large volumes of data in real-time using Kibana.
- Used: Java Springboot to control the server and communicate with the edge devices using Rabbit MQ.

## **Software Developer**

Tata Communications Ltd.

July 2018 - May 2021 Mumbai, MH, IN

- Led the development and design of an internal IPT Tool dashboard for 10,000+ users to monitor login activity, app usage, and security metrics using Django, Python, Javascript, React.
- Automated testing and feature deployments, ensuring reliable and efficient workflows.
- Developed an automation application for Back-Bone Cost Map using Python3 and Leaflet Open Maps, enabling the sales team to identify optimal customer routes and increasing APAC region revenue by 36%.

#### **PROJECTS**

**Nutri Al Scan** 

Vue Js, REST API, Mongo DB

Oct 2022 - Feb 2023

\* Won 2nd place at the CBIC Entrepreneurship at UMBC out of 25+ teams. I developed a progressive web app using OCR to identify allergens and harmful ingredients which provide healthiness ratings for food products.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Harvard Univerity** 

Online

Data Science: Machine Learning

JP Morgan Chase

Online

Advance Software Engineering - Design a System using Kafka, H2, API

## **EDUCATION**

**University of Maryland, Baltimore County** Masters of Science in Computer Science

Baltimore, MD, US August 2021 - May 2023

**University of Mumbai** 

Mumbai, MH, IN August 2014 - May 2018

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology